Welcome back to Apush in under 3
minutes. No time for intros, let's get
into it. Hey, quick question. Do you
like being cold? I personally don't
really like it and a lot of Americans
actually agree with me, which is why in
the 1980s, millions of Americans will
migrate to the Sun Belt. The reason
being the hotter temperatures and
opportunities, which will cause these
regions to gain more political power.
But, moving on, after 1965, when that
whole immigration act was passed,
immigration steadily rose following the
'60s, but then you see it spike like
crazy in the 1980s. And this happens
because of a collection of things. The
first thing is that the US enacted the
Refugee Act of 1980, which just simply
adopted a humanitarian approach to
admitting and resettling refugees. But,
the bigger thing here is a whole lot of
bad things around the world happened all
at once. For example, Mexico and Cuba
both go through an economic crisis. El
Salvador, Guatemala, and Nicaragua all
go through civil wars. Communism will
force thousands to flee from Vietnam,
Cambodia, and Laos. And Iran also goes
through a revolution. And many people
also left the Philippines, Korea, and
India. Now, you don't need to
necessarily memorize these all. I just
want to show you that a lot of stuff
happened all at once, which caused so
many different immigrants to enter the
United States in the 1980s. The big
effect you see here is what our society
has become now in the present. America
is so culturally diverse as a country
that there are so many bilingual
communities and lots of culture from
other countries, I am sure you see all
over the place. And another big effect
of this is that immigrants will often
fill many blue-collar jobs, meaning many
labor-based jobs in America. But, the
other big thing this leads to is the
modern debate surrounding immigration.
Things like border control, legal versus
illegal immigration, bilingual
education, and the more complex
assimilation versus multiculturalism. On
the screen now are AP-style questions
for this topic. Pause now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
Only one more topic to go after this and
I will see you in that topic.